Hello, and welcome to Lesson 38
你好，欢迎来到第38课
of this introduction to calculus with Wolfram U.
的这个微积分导论与Wolfram U。
The topic for this lesson is calculus and programming.
本节课的主题是微积分和程序设计。
Let’s begin with a brief overview of the lesson.
我们先来简单介绍一下本课的内容。
The main point is that there are many problems in calculus
最主要的是，微积分中存在许多问题
where you have to do some operation multiple times—
你必须多次进行某些操作的地方----。
tens or hundreds of times—
几百倍
and a good example of that is Euler’s method.
而欧拉的方法就是一个很好的例子。
Now in Euler’s method, you have a recurrence relation.
现在在欧拉的方法中，你有一个递归关系。
What that means is that you need to compute something step by step.
这意味着，你需要一步步地计算一些东西。
For example, if you want to compute y[10],
例如，如果你想计算y[10]。
you need to work out y[9], y[8], et cetera,
你需要计算出y[9]，y[8]，等等。
and to do this correctly by hand can be very, very tedious.
而要正确地用手去做这件事，是非常非常繁琐的。
You may have errors in your calculations,
你的计算可能有错误。
or it might just take a very long time.
或者说可能要花很长的时间。
Of course what you can do is to set up a program
当然，你可以做的是设置一个程序。
which does that for you in the Wolfram Language.
它在Wolfram语言中为你做到了这一点。
That’s the theme of this lesson.
这就是本课的主题。
In this lesson, you’ll learn how to make
在本课中，你将学习如何制作
your own programs within the Wolfram Language.
在Wolfram语言中，你自己的程序。
We need some preliminaries over here.
我们需要在这里做一些预演。
We need a few tools basically which will let us
我们需要一些工具，基本上，这将让我们
make programs in the Wolfram Language,
用Wolfram语言制作程序。
and that’s just a list of functions which are useful in this context.
而这只是一个在此背景下有用的函数列表。
You need the function If to control the flow of the program.
你需要用函数If来控制程序的流程。
You also need the simple semicolon character
你还需要简单的分号字符。
to stop an instruction and move on to another instruction.
停止一个指令，继续另一个指令。
You need the function Print to put text on the screen
您需要使用打印功能在屏幕上显示文字。
and tell you what is happening inside the program,
并告诉你程序内部发生了什么。
and that’s what is called debugging.
这就是所谓的调试。
Here’s an example of a function which is called ifexample
下面是一个函数的例子，它叫做ifexample。
which takes an input a, a number,
它接收一个输入a，一个数字。
and says if the number a is positive, print “positive”;
并表示如果数字a是正数，则打印"正"。
otherwise, print “not positive”.
否则，打印"不是正数"。
If you apply it to the list over here,
如果你把它应用到这边的名单上。
ifexample[10] should be positive, ifexample[0] should be not positive
ifexample[10]应为正值，ifexample[0]应为负值。
and ifexample[–4] should also be not positive.
和ifexample[-4]也应该不是正数。
Here is the output,
这是输出。
and you see that although you don’t get back anything—
你会发现，虽然你什么都没拿回来... ...
eventually you just get back Null—but on the way,
最终你只是回到Null，但在路上。
you see the positive for the 10
你看到了10的积极性
and the not positive for the remaining two.
而其余两个人的不正。
Now on the next note, if you, let’s say, say a = 5
现在，在接下来的说明中，如果你，比方说，说a=5。
and you put a semicolon over here,
你把一个分号放在这里。
that lets you move on to the next operation,
让你继续进行下一个操作。
which in this case is a + 6.
在这种情况下，它是a+6。
So, a is 5, so of course a + 6 is just 11.
所以，a是5，所以a+6当然只是11。
A couple of things more.
多了几件事情。
You can put comments in your program
您可以在程序中加入注释
using this notation over here,
用这个符号在这里。
and of course comments are very useful
当然，评论是非常有用的
because they explain how your code works.
因为它们解释了你的代码如何工作。
Most code is very hard to read, and unless you have lots of comments,
大多数代码都很难读，除非你有很多注释。
the reader will not be able to tell what’s happening inside the code.
读者将无法知道代码内部发生了什么。
As an example, here I’ve set c equal to 4,
举个例子，这里我将c设为4。
then put a comment to say that we’re setting c equal to 4,
然后加上注释，说明我们将c设为4。
and then it gives the value of c.
然后给出c的值。
Now another important function is the For function,
现在另一个重要的函数是For函数。
which will let you do a task repeatedly
可以让你重复完成一项任务
like we require for the Euler method.
就像我们对欧拉法的要求一样。
Here’s a program that prints the numbers from 1 to 10.
这是一个打印1到10数字的程序。
We start with i = 1 and you go all the way up to 10, not 11.
我们从i=1开始，你一直到10，而不是11。
You keep going as long as the number i is less than 11,
只要数字i小于11，你就继续走。
and at every step, you increment i by 1 to go on to the next number.
而每一步，你都会将i递增1，以进入下一个数字。
Then of course you print the number
然后你当然会打印出数字
to say what’s happening inside the code.
来说说代码里面发生了什么。
Here is the For loop,
这里是For循环。
and you see it prints 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10 and then stops.
你看，它打印1，2，3，4，5，6，7，8，9，10，然后停止。
Okay. Just one more issue,
好吧，还有一个问题还有一个问题
and that’s the issue of global versus local variables.
这就是全局变量与局部变量的问题。
The variable over here a is a global variable in the sense that
这里的变量a是一个全局变量，其意义在于
its value was set earlier to be 5.
其数值早先设定为5。
Now that can be a huge problem for you when you make a program.
现在，当你做一个程序时，这对你来说可能是一个巨大的问题。
For example, you write a function f[x] which just does x + a.
例如，你写一个函数f[x]，它只是做x+a。
If you do f[2], you might think you’ll get back 2 + a,
如果你做f[2]，你可能会认为你会得到回2+a。
but instead you get back 7, and that’s because a is 5.
但你却得到了7，这是因为a是5。
What we need to do is to instead use local variables.
我们需要做的是改用局部变量。
Now you could use different variable names,
现在你可以使用不同的变量名称。
but you might forget what they are,
但你可能会忘记它们是什么。
so the best way out is to use local variables.
所以最好的办法就是使用局部变量。
For example, over here you can use Module,
例如，在这边你可以使用Module。
and what Module does is it localizes the variable a.
而Module所做的就是将变量a本地化。
If I do f[2], then you get back 2 plus this strange kind of a, a$2415.
如果我做f[2]，那么你就会得到2加这种奇怪的a，a2415元。
Now that number might change from time to time,
现在这个数字可能会时常变化。
but basically that protects the a inside the function
但基本上保护了函数中的a。
from being confused with the a which is global.
避免与全局性的a相混淆。
This extra symbol over here indicates that
这里多出来的这个符号表示
it is a local variable or a Module variable.
它是一个局部变量或模块变量。
That’s all we need to define a function
这就是我们需要定义一个函数的全部内容
which implements Euler’s method.
它实现了欧拉的方法。
Recall that that was the one thing
记得那是一件事
we could not quite discuss fully in differential equations.
我们在微分方程中不能完全讨论。
So here’s a function called eulermethod.
所以这里有一个函数叫eulermethod。
Now I’m using lowercase
现在我用的是小写
because the Wolfram Language likes to reserve the uppercase letters
因为 Wolfram 语言喜欢保留大写字母
for built-in functions.
为内置功能。
It takes the slope function, the starting point,
它以斜率函数，为起点。
the end point of the interval, the initial value for the function
区间的终点，函数的初始值。
and the step size—how many steps you want to take as you go along.
和步数--你想走多少步，你就走多少步。
What you do now is you set up a Module,
你现在要做的是设置一个模块。
and the Module has some variables in it.
而Module里有一些变量。
The first variable is m,
第一个变量是m。
and what m is, is just the number of steps to be used.
而m是什么，只是使用的步数。
It’s the end minus the start over the step size.
是终点减去起点超过步幅。
We also need the x values.
我们还需要x值。
That’s going to be the starting value plus the step size times i,
这将是起始值加上步长大小乘以i。
where i will go from 0 to the number of steps.
其中i将从0到步数。
We also need the y values, and to do that,
我们还需要y值，并做到这一点。
we first populate this table with the same constant initial value,
我们首先用相同的常量初始值来填充这个表。
and then we start off with the For loop.
然后我们从For循环开始。
What the For loop does is it calculates each value of y
For循环的作用是计算y的每一个值。
based on the preceding value plus the step size times the slope.
基于前一个值加上步长乘以斜率。
Then finally we gather all the x and y values
最后我们收集所有的x和y值。
and do this Transpose to make them look just right.
并做这个Transpose，让它们看起来恰到好处。
That is Euler’s method from differential equations
这就是微分方程的欧拉法
now done in the Wolfram Language.
现在用Wolfram语言完成。
With this simple function, we can now try and do some calculations.
有了这个简单的函数，我们现在可以尝试着做一些计算。
Here is a differential equation, y' = y given y[0] = 1,
这里是一个微分方程，y'=y，给定y[0]=1。
and of course the solution for that is just e^x.
当然，解决这个问题的方法只是e^x。
The right-hand side is y.
右边是y。
That’s your f.
这是你的f。
We apply the eulermethod to f starting at 0
我们从0开始对f应用eulermethod。
because that’s where you’re starting over here,
因为那是你在这里重新开始的地方。
and you want the value at 2, so that’s where you’ll stop.
而你想要的值是2，所以你会在这里停止。
The initial value is 1.
初始值为1。
That’s the 1 over here.
这是1在这里。
The 0.1 is going to be the step size.
0.1要作为步长大小。
Okay. When you do that, then you see over here that
好吧，当你这样做的时候，当你这样做，那么你看到在这里，
you get back a list of values starting from the initial value
你会得到一个从初始值开始的数值列表。
and going all the way up to 2 in steps of 0.1.
并以0.1为单位一直到2。
Now you see over here that the last value is 6.7275.
现在你看这边，最后一个值是6.7275。
The estimate over here is that the value of y[2] is 6.7275.
这边的估计是y[2]的值是6.7275。
Let’s compare that with e^2, and it looks like it’s reasonably good,
我们用e^2来比较一下，看起来好像还不错。
but not very accurate.
但不是很准确。
But that’s because we’re only at a step size of 0.1.
但这是因为我们的步长只有0.1。
Because you’re working on a computer,
因为你是在电脑上工作。
you can afford to make much smaller steps.
你可以负担得起更小的步骤。
You could say let the step size be 0.001,
你可以说让步长为0.001。
and then you get back a much smaller estimate for the error,
然后你会得到一个小得多的估计误差。
which is 0.007.
即0.007。
The point is that you can get better estimates for the values
关键是，你可以得到更好的估计值。
and much smaller errors simply by decreasing the step size.
只需减小步长，误差就会小得多。
Of course because it’s all automatic, it doesn’t matter.
当然因为都是自动的，所以无所谓。
You can go quite a long way to get more and more accurate results.
要想获得更多更准确的结果，你可以走相当长的路。
Okay. That brings me to the end of the lesson,
好了，我的课就到此为止了我的课到此结束。
and the main point is that
而主要的是
the Wolfram Language is great for making programs.
Wolfram语言是制作程序的好帮手。
In fact, what you’ve done in this course
事实上，你在这门课上所做的事情
is to learn many parts of the Wolfram Language
是学习Wolfram语言的许多部分。
in the context of calculus, and that’s a great thing to know.
在微积分的背景下，这是一个伟大的事情，知道。
Programming is a big plus in this age.
在这个时代，编程是一个很大的优势。
Now to program, you need functions like If, For, Print and Module.
现在要编程，你需要If、For、Print和Module等功能。
Do not forget—try and put as many comments as you can
不要忘了尝试，并把尽可能多的意见，你可以。
because they are crucial for understanding
因为它们对于理解
what you are trying to do, both for yourself and for others.
你想做什么，无论是为了自己还是为了别人。
Try to avoid global variables.
尽量避免全局变量。
Try and use local variables to avoid confusion,
尽量使用局部变量以避免混淆。
and you can do that with Module.
而你可以通过Module来实现。
We saw that we can program Euler’s method,
我们看到，我们可以用欧拉的方法编程。
but of course you can program other calculus operations,
但当然你也可以编程进行其他的微积分运算。
like finding maxima and minima, using the Wolfram Language.
比如使用Wolfram语言寻找最大值和最小值。
To program yourself means that you actually become
程式化意味着你实际上成为
some kind of an expert on the Wolfram Language
沃尔夫兰语言专家
because those programs can be quite hard to write.
因为那些程序可能相当难写。
That’s the end of this lesson on calculus and programming.
这节课的微积分和程序设计就到此为止。
We’re really done with the course content.
我们真的完成了课程内容的学习。
In the next lesson, we’ll talk about a sample calculus exam,
下节课，我们就来讲讲微积分考试的样题。
the first part of the exam, but until then,
第一部分的考试，但在那之前。
do review this lesson and be prepared to take on an exam.
做好本课的复习，做好考试的准备。
Thank you very much. I’ll stop over here.
这节课到这就结束了 谢谢观看